William Setzer

william@setzer.tech · 334-300-7107 · linkedin.com/in/william-setzer Professional programmer | Python enthusiast | Problem solver

SUMMARY

Customer-focused professional with a passion for data science offering experience in computer programming, data collection, data processing, and analysis, with knowledge in Python, Golang, Java, and relational databases.

Skills and Languages

- Strong knowledge of Python, Java, Golang, Linux
- Good knowledge of PostgreSQL and Snowflake
- Familiar with JavaScript, Ruby, and Scala
- · Beginner proficiency in German

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Computer Science with Honors, *Magna Cum Laude* University of Alabama at Birmingham GPA: 3.81

May 2018 Birmingham, Alabama

WORK EXPERIENCE

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

August 2021 – Present

BIRMINGHAM, ALABAMA

SHIPT

- Utilized Python and later a combination of Python and Golang for efficient ingestion of partners' catalog data
- Enhanced our data ingestion framework by implementing parallel and asynchronous processing to handle large partner files and varied partner APIs
- Streamlined the onboarding process for new retail partners by creating a data mapping template
- Managed program execution through Airflow and GCS Cloud Console
- Facilitated data transfer between services using AWS, GCS, and Kafka
- Contributed to the overhaul of the ingestion system by leveraging Golang
- Collaborated in the design and implementation of new features and APIs
- · Ensured code reliability through creation and maintenance of robust unit and integration tests
- · Collaborated with other teams to maintain data integrity and quickly remediate issues

JUNIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

May 2020 - August 2021

Birmingham, Alabama

- Operated as a junior software developer at Blue Cross and Blue Shield of Alabama.
- Contributed to the development and maintenance of the *my*BlueCross website using Java, JavaScript, and HTML.
- Designed and implemented REST API endpoints in the Spring framework for Java.
- Wrote queries in SQL for IBM Db2 and integrated them into Spring with JDBC.
- Modernized the style of web pages according to specification using CSS and SCSS.
- · Conducted unit tests and documented features using JUnit
- Collaborated effectively with team members to achieve project goals

Cyber Security Engineer

JUNE 2019 – MAY 2020

BIRMINGHAM, ALABAMA

Regions Bank

SENECA RESOURCES

- Redesigned processes to align with modern standards and best practices
- Automated SOC processes using the Splunk Phantom platform.
- Developed playbooks, automation scripts, and product integrations within Phantom.
- Integrated the SOAR platform with a range of products to provide automation actions for workflows.
- Migrated content from Demisto to Splunk's Phantom platform

RESEARCH/TEACHING ASSISTANT

August 2017 – June 2019

UAB DEPARTMENT OF COMPUTER SCIENCE

Birmingham, Alabama

 Collected data using Python, Ruby, and PostgreSQL from Reddit and alternative social media sites and forums, e.g. 4chan, 8chan, Minds.

- Analyzed collected data with Python and Hadoop to find statistical patterns, producing plots to visualize the data using various plots, e.g. CDFs, CCDFs, joint distributions, and basic scatter and line plots.
- Used change point analysis to correlate changes in the patterns of data collected to real-world events.
- Instructed lab sections for both Introduction to Computer Science and Computer Architecture, teaching and assisting a wide variety of students as they learned Python in the introductory course and x86 Assembly in the computer architecture course.
- Graded homework assignments.

PROGRAMMING TEAM LEAD & PROGRAMMER

April 2017 – August 2018

UAB Computer Forensics Research Lab

BIRMINGHAM, ALABAMA

- Supervised the programming team, ensuring the quality of code and the delivery of tools for use by the lab's cyber-crime analysts.
- Established effective use of version control and documentation practices.
- Conducted programmer interviews and onboarded new team members.
- Created efficient web scrapers to scrape forums in **Python** using packages including *Requests*, *lxml*, *aiohttp*, *AsyncIO*, *multiprocessing*, and *Selenium*.
- Transitioned web scraping in the lab from synchronously usinig Selenium to Requests, AsyncIO, and aiohttp to create faster web scrapers.
- Created a web forum database for scrapers in **PostgreSQL** to replace multiple non-standardized ways of storing forum data.
- Set up and maintained a MongoDB instance for collecting a variety of non-standard data collected from the web.

BARISTA
STARBUCKS

MAY 2016 – NOVEMBER 2016
BIRMINGHAM, ALABAMA

Cashier

January 2016 – May 2016

Chick-fil-A

Birmingham, Alabama

PROSTHETIC TECHNICIAN

ALABAMA ARTIFICIAL LIMB AND ORTHOTICS SERVICE

MAY 2013 – JUNE 2013, DECEMBER 2015 – JANUARY 2016

MONTGOMERY, ALABAMA

Website Product Entry
Beth's Heirloom Sewing

June 2014 – August 2014
Wetumpka, Alabama

Awards and Leadership

• UAB President's List Spring 2016, Fall 2016, Fall 2017, Spring 2018

• UAB Dean's List Fall 2015, Spring 2017

• UAB Presidential Scholarship Fall 2014 – Spring 2018

• Vermeer Corporation Scholarship 2014, 2016